[
    {
        "question": "What is the process at the most detailed level of the data flow diagrams known as?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) The process at the most detailed level of the data flow diagrams known as functional primitives",
        "options": [
            "Interfaces",
            "functional primitives",
            "data flow",
            "transform descriptions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total bits used by the IPv6 address is ________",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Total bits used by the IPv6 address is 128 bits.",
        "options": [
            "64 bit",
            "256 bit",
            "128 bit",
            "32 bit"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the language which is mainly used for Artificial Intelligence",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Prolog is used for Artificial Intelligence.",
        "options": [
            "Java",
            "J2EE",
            "Prolog",
            "C"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is a firewall used in a computer?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Firewall is used in computers for security.",
        "options": [
            "Monitoring",
            "data transmission",
            "Authentication",
            "security"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The full form of DOM is?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) DOM  stands for document object model.",
        "options": [
            "Document-oriented memory",
            "document object model",
            "document object memory",
            "none"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many levels are there in the architecture of the database?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) There are three levels of architecture in the database - physical level, the view level, and user level.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which is not a database management software",
        "answer": "Answer: B) COBOL  is not a database management software",
        "options": [
            "MySQL",
            "COBOL",
            "Sybase",
            "Oracle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the total standard color names that HTML supports.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) HTML supports a total of 140 standard color names.",
        "options": [
            "30",
            "70",
            "140",
            "120"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the port number of FTP.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) The port number of FTP is 21",
        "options": [
            "23",
            "21",
            "110",
            "143"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total number of layers in OSI model is ___________",
        "answer": "Answer: B) The total number of layers in the OSI model is 7.",
        "options": [
            "5",
            "7",
            "9",
            "11"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "UNIX is written in which language?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) UNIX is written in C language. It was developed in the 1970s at AT & T Bell laboratories.",
        "options": [
            "C#",
            "C++",
            "C",
            ".Net"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the different features of Big Data Analytics.",
        "answer": "Answer: D)  All of the above are features of Big Data Analytics",
        "options": [
            "open source",
            "data recovery",
            "Scalability",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an extension of image file?",
        "answer": "Answer: B)  .gif is an extension of image file.",
        "options": [
            ".mkv",
            ".gif",
            ".txt",
            ".vdf"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Dbase III is?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) dBase III is Application software.",
        "options": [
            "Hardware",
            "Firmware",
            "application software",
            "operating system"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The main memory of a computer system is?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Main memory of a computer system is volatile",
        "options": [
            "Non-volatile",
            "Volatile",
            "Restricted",
            "Unrestricted"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following servers which allow LAN users to share data.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) File server allows LAN users to share data.",
        "options": [
            "Communication server",
            "Point server",
            "Data server",
            "File server"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "URL stands for _______________",
        "answer": "Answer: D) The full form of URL is a uniform resource locator.",
        "options": [
            "Uninterrupted data locator",
            "Uninterrupted record locator",
            "uniform record locator",
            "uniform resource locator"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "SSLstands for _______________",
        "answer": "Answer: A) The full form of SSL is a secure socket layer.",
        "options": [
            "secure socket layer",
            "secure secret level",
            "secure system level",
            "section security layer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a SQL command?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) DELETE is not a SQL command",
        "options": [
            "DELETE",
            "ORDER BY",
            "SELECT",
            "WHERE"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the range of byte data types in JavaScript",
        "answer": "Answer: B) the range of byte data type is - 128 to 127.",
        "options": [
            "-10 to 9",
            "- 128 to 127",
            "-32768 to 32767",
            "-2147483648 to 2147483647"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Computer word size is a multiple of ______ bits",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Computer word size is a multiple of 16 bits",
        "options": [
            "4 bits",
            "10 bits",
            "16 bits",
            "1024 bits"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "OCR stands for _____________",
        "answer": "Answer: D) OCR stands for optical card reader.",
        "options": [
            "Online computer retrieval",
            "office cash receiver",
            "optical character reader",
            "optical card reader"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Testing of program’s corporate is known as?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Testing of program’s corporate is known as unit testing.",
        "options": [
            "System testing",
            "isolation testing",
            "pilot testing",
            "unit-testing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Information in computer read-only memory stored by",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Information in computer read-only memory is stored by the manufacturer.",
        "options": [
            "Engineer",
            "Programmer",
            "Manufacturer",
            "user"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Device driver required in?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) A disk drive is a device driver that allows a specific disk drive to communicate with the remainder of the computer. A good example of this driver is a floppy disk drive.",
        "options": [
            "Register",
            "Main memory",
            "Disk",
            "Cache"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the call which never returns an error?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) The call getpid never returns an error",
        "options": [
            "fork",
            "getpid",
            "ioctl",
            "open"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The total view of a database is known as?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) The conceptual view is referred to as the total view of a database",
        "options": [
            "Physical view",
            "Internal view",
            "Conceptual view",
            "External view"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does computer hardware consist of?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) computer hardware consists of All of the above.",
        "options": [
            "storage devices",
            "CPU",
            "I/O devices",
            "all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In what terms is Computer memory measured?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Computer memory is measured in terms of bytes.",
        "options": [
            "Units",
            "Bits",
            "Cells",
            "bytes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following memory of the computer is volatile?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) RAM is volatile.",
        "options": [
            "EEPROM",
            "RAM",
            "ROM",
            "CMOS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following computer memory users cannot write any information or instruction?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Users cannot write any information or instruction on ROM.",
        "options": [
            "EEPROM",
            "RAM",
            "ROM",
            "CMOS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following commands in UNIX is used to send a signal?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) kill is used to send a signal in UNIX",
        "options": [
            "send",
            "kill",
            "sigsend",
            "none"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Using which of the following is the interconnection of the computer possible?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Using information technology, interconnection of computer is possible.",
        "options": [
            "communication links",
            "Cables",
            "information technology",
            "processing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is computer firmware present?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Computer firmware is present in non-volatile memory.",
        "options": [
            "Cache memory",
            "non-volatile memory",
            "Volatile memory",
            "RAM"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "LPT stands for ______________",
        "answer": "Answer: C) LPT stands for Line printer.",
        "options": [
            "Low print typewriter",
            "line per text",
            "line printer",
            "laser printer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What are modern computers based on?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Modern computers are based on both microchips and microprocessors.",
        "options": [
            "Microchip",
            "Microprocessor",
            "I/O devices",
            "both a and b"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What else is a command interpreter called?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) A command interpreter is also called the shell.",
        "options": [
            "prompt",
            "kernel",
            "command",
            "shell"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The computer system which uses a drum plotter is known as?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Computer system which uses drum plotter is known as both mini and mainframe computer.",
        "options": [
            "mini computer",
            "Mainframe computer",
            "Both A and B",
            "none"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is known as an uninterruptible unit?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Atomic is known as an uninterruptible unit. That is, whenever a process start executes, it doesn’t terminate or context switch until its complete execution",
        "options": [
            "single",
            "static",
            "atomic",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can the data be updated?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Data can be updated in an operational environment",
        "options": [
            "Informational environment",
            "Data warehouse environment",
            "Operational environment",
            "Data mining environment"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the one which is not a networking device.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Traffic analyzer is not a networking device",
        "options": [
            "Switch",
            "Traffic analyzer",
            "Bridge",
            "Router"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The standard length of the MAC address is",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Standard length of MAC address is 48 bits",
        "options": [
            "16 bits",
            "48 bits",
            "32 bits",
            "8 bits"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an operating system?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Oracle is not an operating system. It is a relational database management system, also known as Oracle Database",
        "options": [
            "Linux",
            "DOS",
            "Oracle",
            "Windows"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Through API, _____ service portability is enabled.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Through API, systems service portability is enabled",
        "options": [
            "device",
            "network",
            "services",
            "systems"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a table joined with itself called?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Table joined with self is known as Self Join",
        "options": [
            "Join",
            "Self-join",
            "Outer join",
            "Equi join"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a single-user operating system?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Ms-DOS is a single-user operating system.",
        "options": [
            "Windows",
            "Ms-DOS",
            "MAC",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose among the following, which is the most common internet protocol.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) SMTP is the most commonly used internet protocol.",
        "options": [
            "PPP",
            "FTP",
            "TCP/IP",
            "SMTP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of SBC is?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) SBC stands for Smart business center",
        "options": [
            "Standard business center",
            "Smart business center",
            "Standard building center",
            "Smart building center"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Another name of reading operation in?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Read operation is also known as fetch operation.",
        "options": [
            "store operations",
            "access operation",
            "Fetch operation",
            "control operation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total number of users that can use a microprocessor at a time?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Only a single user can use a microprocessor at a time",
        "options": [
            "Single users",
            "Multi-user",
            "particular user",
            "professional user"
        ]
    }
]